

Tianzhu Zhang

Doctor of Philosophy



18 August, 1989



23 Avenue d'Italie, 75013 Paris, France



+33 669166875



www.linkedin.com/in/tianzhu-zhang-a390485b/



tianzhu.zhang 1989@gmail.com

About me —

I was born in Benxi, a small town in northeast China. In 2014, I was admitted to the PhD program of Politecnico di Torino and started my career as a researcher since then. I have been working with Prof. Paolo Giaccone, who was my PhD supervisor and career mentor. From November 2017, I have been working as a PostDoc researcher at Telecom ParisTech and LINCs Lab, under the support of Cisco Systems. Before that, I also did an internship at Nokia Bell Labs. My main research interest include Software Defined Networking and Network Function Virtualization.

Skills -

Research

Development

Communication

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Education

2018	Doctor of Philosophy Politecnico di Torino & T	Department of Electronics and Telecommunications Telecom Italia, Turin, Italy
2014	Master of Science Politecnico di Torino, Tui	Department of Electronics and Telecommunications rin, Italy
2012	Bachelor of Science	Department of Computer Science and Technology

Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China

Collaborators: Prof. Dario Rossi, Prof. Luigi Iannone

Experience

2017-now

	Telecom ParisTech & Cisco Systems & LINCS Lab, Paris, France	
2017	Intern Nokia Bell Labs, Pari	Collaborators: Dr. Massimo Gallo, Dr. Fabio Pianese s, France
2014-2015	PhD Engineer Telecom Italia, Turin	Collaborators: Dr. Pino Castrogiovanni, Dr. Claudio Borean , Italy

Community Activities

PostDoc Researcher

Communicati	ricy / territies
2020	TPC Member IEEE Conference on Network Softwarization
2020	TPC Member 23rd Conference on Innovation in Clouds, Internet and Networks
2019	Volunteer IEEE International Conference on Computer Communications
2018	Shadow PC Reviewer ACM Internet Measurement Conference
2016-2019	Reviewer IEEE Communications Letters, Computer Communications (Elsevier)

Main Publications

Tianzhu Zhang, Leonardo Linguaglossa, Massimo Gallo, Paolo Giaccone, Luigi Iannone, James Roberts. "Comparing the performance of state-of-the-art software switches for NFV", ACM CoNEXT 2019.

Tianzhu Zhang, Leonardo Linguaglossa, Massimo Gallo, Paolo Giaccone, Dario Rossi, "FloWatcher-DPDK: lightweight line-rate flow-level monitoring in software", IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management (2019).

Tianzhu Zhang, Leonardo Linguaglossa, Massimo Gallo, Paolo Giaccone, Dario Rossi, "FlowMon-DPDK: Parsimonious per-flow software monitoring at line rate", IEEE/IFIP TMA, 2018.

Tianzhu Zhang, Paolo Giaccone, Andrea Bianco, Samuele De Domenico, "The role of the inter-controller consensus in the placement of distributed SDN controllers", Computer Communications (2017).

Tianzhu Zhang, Andrea Bianco, Paolo Giaccone, "The role of inter-controller traffic in SDN controllers placement", IEEE NFV-SDN, 2016.

Tianzhu Zhang, Carla Fabiana Chiasserini, Paolo Giaccone, "TAME: An efficient task allocation algorithm for integrated mobile gaming", IEEE Systems Journal (2018).